Howard Ting

2197 Cuesta Dr., Milpitas, CA 95035

Email: cuberuru@gmail.com, <a href="https://https

SUMMARY:

I'm a new graduate with experience working in small and large software development projects. I've tutored advanced computer science courses and have developed some experience in web and game development in my free time; I seek to leverage my computer science background to professional work.

EDUCATION:

University of California, Santa Cruz

B.S in Computer Science, GPA: 3.2

Related Coursework:

Software Methodology (project management & documentation methods: e.g. scrum/standup), Introduction to Probability Theory, Software Design Project I &II (Android Mobile; Java), Introduction to Algorithm Analysis, Fundamentals of Compiler Design (C++), Introduction to Data Structures (C/Java), Computational Models, Introduction to Operating Systems (C), Algorithms & Abstract Data Type (C/Java), Comparative Programming Languages (Scheme, OCAML, Smalltalk, Prolog)

TECHNICAL SKILLS:

- Proficient in C++
- Competent in C, JavaScript, HTML/CSS, Java
- Exposure to C#, Unity, MySQL
- Tools/IDE: Unix, Github, C9, Bracket, Atom, Sublime, Android Studio
- English/Mandarin Proficiency

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE:

Tutor, Learning Support Services

Oct 2017 - Dec 2017

Graduated: December 2017

- Introduction to Compiler Design Create weekly lesson plans to tutor small groups, reviewed course project architecture (written in C++) and compiler design concepts
- Introduction to Analysis of Algorithms reviewed algorithm concepts with single student

Developer, Calm Stop (Mobile)

Jan 2017 -- Jun 2017

- Developed mobile app with team of 4 in a fast-paced, iterative development environment (i.e. agile) while learning how to use Android Studio to build a mobile application for our sponsor, Police Strategies: http://scalesstrategic.com/
- Set up the UI and backend for the app's login and signup, created the initial functioning UI/code prototype of
 the app's chat messaging system, and imported an API (glide) to create a photo upload and reception
 module. The team used Firebase extensively as our intermediary database for all transmissions and data
 storage
- Implemented in Android Studio & written in Java

Developer, Game Design Art Collab

Sep 2015 -- Jun 2017

- Collaborated with teams consisting of 20-50 students on single games (1/yr)
- Sep 2015 Jun 2016: Built & designed an inventory system using Unity C# for the game, COMA
- Jan 2017 Jun 2017: Composed and exported music MIDI using Musescore for the game, RAIJU

OTHER:

- Web Development developed websites for personal use (e.g. howardtingling.github.io)
- Waiter/Cashier bussed tables and interfaced with customers; occasionally washed dishes in the back